keenfootwear.com 2018-12-12

# Customer Service - Legal | KEEN Footwear

**Information you give us**

You may give us information, including information that can identify you ("personal information"), when you use our Websites, correspond with us, or enter into any of our competitions, promotions, sweepstakes or surveys. Where we request information from you, we will collect the information set out in the relevant forms or pages. You may choose to provide additional information to us when you contact us or otherwise interact with us. 

If you purchase any products through the Websites you may be required to create an online account (your "Account"). You are also able to create an Account with us without placing any orders. You may also be able to place orders without creating an Account via the "Guest Checkout" feature. 

The information that you provide when setting up your Account may include your name, email address and telephone number. If you register to hold an Account with us, you will also have a unique username and password which enables you to access your Account. 

Please note that we will not be storing your payment information, which will be processed and stored by a third party payments company (e.g. PayPal or Paymentech), although we may store certain information like your billing address and the last 4 digits of your card number. 

If you subscribe to receive our newsletter, then you will provide us with your name and email address (and possibly even your relevant interests!) although you may optionally also provide your gender and date of birth. 

If you contact us via email then we will collect your email address. 

You may also submit personal information in connection with photos/stories/videos for our potential use and/or publication (for example, as part of competitions) or via reviews or our message boards. We may use some of these in marketing campaigns but if we do we will ensure that you are made aware of such use prior to the campaign going live and given an opportunity to understand the intended use and, if you choose, object to the use. 

The personal information that you provide to us will be used for the purposes made clear to you at the time you submit your information, for example for enabling you to use our Websites and placing orders online and/or for administrative and troubleshooting purposes, and, as explained in section titled "Information we receive from other sources,” we may also use this information for further purposes when combined with other data we collect about you. 

We and our third party marketing partners may also use the information you send to us for our marketing purposes, if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences. However, you will always be able to opt-out of our marketing at any time (see the "How to opt in or opt out of direct marketing" section below). 

**Information we collect automatically via the Websites**

When you visit our Websites, we may automatically collect the following information: your IP address, log-in information, location information, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, information about your visit including the URL clickstream to, through and from our Websites, download errors, length of visits to certain pages and page interaction. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area, this information may be considered personal information under applicable data protection laws. We collect information automatically through the use of various technologies, including through "cookies", and this is explained further in the "Cookies and other technologies" section below. 

We use the information we collect automatically: (i) to administer our Websites for internal operations including troubleshooting purposes; (ii) to ensure that content from our Websites is presented in the most effective manner for you and your devices; (iii) as part of our effort to keep our Websites and the order process; (iv) to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; and (v) to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Websites about goods or services that may interest you or them. 

**Information we receive from other sources**

We may receive and collect information about you if you access the Websites via social media (or vice versa) or if you use our forums, enter competitions with us or one of our partners or upload any content to the Websites. We use this information to provide technical support, validate your identity and enable your participation in any competitions you enter. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them (including information that is publicly available). 

Where permitted by law, we may combine this information we receive from other sources, including from social media websites, with information you give to us and information we collect about you, including cookie information. We may use this information and the combined information for learning more about your preferences as our customer, for enhancing your user experience on our Websites and for providing you with information, content and offerings tailored to your needs. 

**Pro Site users**

In addition to the above collection and use, if you wish to access and make use of our Pro Sites we may require certain other information from you to validate your identity and employment status at an eligible partnering brand. We may require certain information from or photographs of your paystubs/payslips or your work email address that you use at our partner. We will make you aware of what is required when you access our Pro Sites. 

We will only ever ask you for a proportionate and justified amount of personal information to allow us to carry out the above checks and will not store this information for an unreasonable length of time. 

**Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)**

If you are a visitor from the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests (such as the prevention of fraud or provision of direct marketing) and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person. If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

**If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us at the address found in the "Contact Us" section below.**

**Cookies and other technologies**

We collect information automatically through the use of "cookies". A cookie is a text file containing small amounts of information that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a tag that distinguishes your computer but does not name you. Some of our websites pages use cookies to better serve you when you return to the Websites. For information about the specific cookies used on these Websites and how you can block or turn off cookies, please refer to our Cookie Statement. 

**Do Not Track**

Some Internet browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals. Since uniform standards for “Do Not Track” signals have not been adopted, our websites do not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals. To learn more about “Do Not Track”, please visit [All About Do Not Track.](https://allaboutdnt.com/)

**Links to other websites and social media**

Where we provide links to other websites, we do so for information purposes only. The other websites are outside our control and are not covered by this Policy. If you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. On some pages of our Websites, third parties that provide content, applications or plug-ins through our Websites may track your use of content, applications and plug-ins or customize content, applications and plug-ins for you.  For more information, please refer to our Cookie Statement. 

**Data retention**

We may retain some information about you and your purchases after they have been placed or your account has been closed where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

**Disclosure of information to third parties**

We may share your information with third parties: (1) when it is necessary to involve a third party service provider in order to facilitate or extend our services; (2) when explicitly requested by you (e.g. with social media networks); (3) when required by a court order or any legal or regulatory requirement; (4) to enforce our user agreements or policies, such as the Terms of Sale and Terms of Use; (5) to ensure the safety and security of our users, consumers and third parties; (6) to protect our rights and property and the rights and property of our guests and third parties; (7) with selected third parties for their own services and marketing purposes, unless you opt out of this type of sharing by following the directions in Part III below; and (8) with your consent to fulfil the purposes communicated to you at the time of collection. We may request your consent to share your personal information with some third parties in other situations not listed above and, in this circumstance, we will only share your personal information with parties for whom you have consented. 

In the event that we or substantially all of our assets is purchased by or transferred to another company, some personal information may be an asset that is reviewed and transferred by or to a third party. This means that if a third party buys us, a corporate group member or its assets, then we may disclose information to that third party in connection with the sale. We will make clear to the relevant third party purchaser that it should only use personal information it receives from us for the purposes for which it was originally obtained.
